Funnuraba!
(銀時)ふんぬらば～！
うぅ… ｵﾒｴ ﾀﾞﾒだって！
こんなところで用足したら｡
Hey, you can't do your business here...
Your excretion is bigger than
a naughty monk's dreams!
お前の排泄物は わんぱく坊主の
夢より でっかいんだから！
ﾁｸｼｮｳ！ だから ｲﾔだったんだよ｡
Damn it!
That's why I didn't want this...
｢あとで 絶対
散歩に連れていくｱﾙ｣って➡
She's the one who said she'd
take him for a walk later!
言ってたくせによ！
But in the end, your mother
has to do all the work!
あとでって 絶対 結局
最終的には➡
お母さんが 犬の世話することに
なるんだよ｡
あれ？ ｵﾚ お母さん？
Wait, I'm the mother?
(桂)ﾌﾝ… ﾍﾟｯﾄのしつけも
できんとは 情けない｡
You can't even keep a
pet in line... Pathetic.
(桂)動物１匹
自由にできんようで➡
How can you change this nation when you
can't even hold an animal in check?
天下国家を
どうして動かせようか｡
And you call yourself a samurai?
ｷｻﾏ それでも侍か？
隣の… 何？
What is that next to you?
["It's What's On The Inside That Counts"]
[Battle Royal Host]
Honestly, you're such a pain.
まったく お前には 困ったものだ｡
定春君を飼い始めて いったい
どれくらいになるというのだ？
How long have you had Sadaharu-kun?
いまだに 主人とﾍﾟｯﾄの関係が
構築されていないではないか｡
You still haven't established a
master and pet relationship.
Right, Elizabeth?
なぁ？ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
主人とﾍﾟｯﾄの信頼関係は
日本海よりも深く➡
A true bond of trust between a master and
pet must be deeper than the Sea of Japan
長州の後ろ髪よりも
長いものでなければ➡
and longer than Choshu's mullet.
[Note: Riki Choshu is a professional
wrestler known for his mullet.]
本物とは言えん｡ なぁ？ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
Right, Elizabeth?
ん？ どうした？ 銀時
そのﾊﾟﾌｪ 食べぬのか？
What is it, Gintoki?
You aren't going to eat that parfait?
食べぬのなら ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽに
食わせてやってもよいか？
If you aren't, would you
mind if Elizabeth had it?
なぁ？ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
Right, Elizabeth?
っていうか それ
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽじゃなくね？
Yeah... That isn't Elizabeth, is it?
ﾊﾊﾊ！ 銀時 お前にしては➡
Gintoki, that was a pretty
witty American joke.
ずいぶん小じゃれた
ｱﾒﾘｶﾝｼﾞｮｰｸではないか｡
誰も ｼﾞｮｰｸ言ってねえよ！
I wasn't telling a joke!
And how was that even American?!
つうか いったい
どのへんが ｱﾒﾘｶﾝなんだよ!?
Hell, that thing's the one
that looks Americanized!
むしろ ｿｲﾂが ｱﾒﾘｶﾝだろ！
ｱﾒﾘｶ帰りのﾔﾂ
そっくりじゃねえか！
["I'm Russianized"]
How would I know that?!
知らねえよ！ 何だよ その設定！
And why are you using a Bentendo
TS to talk to me?!
[Note: Parody of Nintendo DS]
その前に なんで ﾍﾞﾝﾃﾝﾄﾞｰＴＳで
会話しようとしてんだよ!?
いつもの看板で いいだろ！
Use your usual sign!
つうか お前 大丈夫か？
Anyways, are you okay?
何か 悪いもんでも
食っちゃったんじゃないの？
Did you eat something rotten?
Did you eat something off the floor?
道に落ちてたもん 拾い食い
しちゃったんじゃないの？
人生という道になら いつでも
小さな希望が落ちていよう｡
As you go through life, it is always
possible to find hope lying around...
んなことは聞いてねえよ｡
That's not what I asked.
This is bad. Definitely bad.
やばいよ 絶対やばいよ｡
You were bad to begin with, but you've taken
it to a whole new level today, Zura.
ふだんから やばかったけど
今日は 特にやばいだろ ﾂﾞﾗ｡
ﾂﾞﾗじゃない 桂だ｡
It's Katsura, not Zura.
とにかく 我々は いつまでも➡
In any case, we don't have time
to listen to your foolishness.
お前の戯言に
付き合っていられん｡
Let's go, Elizabeth.
行こう ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
あ ありがとうございました…｡
Th-Thank you very much...
[Note: This is a 10,000 yen bill. 10,000 yen
is equivalent to USD $100.]
あ ありがとうございました｡
今 お釣りを｡
Th-Thank you very much.
I'll go get your change.
["Keep the change"]
Thank you very much!
Thank you so very much!
ありがとうございます｡
ありがとうございました！
♪♪～
ﾊﾊﾊ！ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ ずいぶん
箸の使い方が 下手になったな｡
Elizabeth, you seem to have forgotten
how to use chopsticks.
まぁいい またｵﾚが
一から教えてやろう｡
No matter. I'll teach you
from the beginning.
Since we live in a land of chopsticks.
ここは 箸の国だからな
ﾊﾊﾊ！ ﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
I-Indeed...
(新八)た 確かに
銀さんの言ってたとおり➡
It's just like Gin-san said.
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽじゃなくなってる｡
It's no longer the Elizabeth we know.
ｲﾒﾁｪﾝってﾚﾍﾞﾙじゃないですね｡
That's no simple makeover.
(神楽)ﾊﾟﾁﾓﾝにも見えないｱﾙ｡
もう 別物ね｡
Doesn't even look like a fake.
It's something completely different.
I wonder what happened
to the real Elizabeth.
本物のｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…
どうしちゃったんだろう？
おいおい なんでお前たち
しんみりしてんの？
Hey now...
Why are you getting all gloomy?
当たり前ですよ！
Why wouldn't we?!
ﾎﾞｸだって
桂さんほどじゃないけど➡
I might not be able to compare
with Katsura-san,
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽとの思い出は
あるんですから｡
but I have my own share of fond
memories with Elizabeth.
私もね！
Me too!
All of the memories are so beautiful.
思い出すのは
きれいな思い出ばかりよ｡
いや これ 全然きれいな
思い出じゃねえんだけど｡
No, there's nothing beautiful about that.
And wait, why are you remembering
last night's dinner?
っていうか 昨日の夕飯
思い出して どうすんの？
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ関係なくね？
That has nothing to do with Elizabeth.
I'll find a way to wake Katsura-san up!
ﾎﾞｸがなんとかして
桂さんの目を覚まさせます！
Katsura-san will surely be sad when
he realizes what's happened!
桂さんだって 気づけば
絶対 悲しむはずです！
そうね あんなﾊﾟﾁﾓﾝ
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽの風上にもおけないね！
Right on!
That fake can't hold a
candle to Elizabeth!
しかし 普通に ｵﾚたちが
何言っても➡
But Zura usually won't listen
to anything we have to say.
ﾂﾞﾗのﾔﾂは 聞かねえからな｡
しかたねえ
なんとか気づかせてやるか｡
No choice then...
We'll try to wake him up.
Excuse me, you two.
すみません そこの２人｡
いやぁ どうもどうも｡
Why hello there...
なんですか あなたたち？
What's with you people?
いやぁ 私たち
ﾍﾟｯﾄ愛護団体の者でして｡
Well, we happen to belong
to a pet-loving society.
There's been a rise in the number of people
keeping illegal animals as pets
最近ですね 不法の生物を
持ち込んではﾍﾟｯﾄにして飼ったり➡
人様のﾍﾟｯﾄを盗んで
自分のものにしたりしている➡
or stealing other people's pets.
輩が多いんですよ｡
なんだと｡
What was that?!
Are you implying that I'm one
of those evil villains?!
ｵﾚがそのような
不届きな輩だとでもいうのか？
不届きっていうか ﾊﾞｶなんですね｡
More stupid than evil.
いやいやいや
そういうわけじゃなくてですね｡
No, no, no! That wasn't our intention.
それが 本当にお宅のﾍﾟｯﾄか➡
We simply wanted to check
if that was really your pet.
調べさせてもらいたい
だけなんです｡
Please cooperate!
ご協力お願いします｡
しかたがない｡
I have no choice...
So what am I supposed to do?
で 何をすればよいのだ？
Could you start by providing
some form of ID?
とりあえず なにか身分を
証明できるものを➡
見せてもらえないですかね｡
そちらのﾍﾟｯﾄの｡
For the pet.
Uh, it'd be pretty odd for
a pet to have any ID.
いや ﾍﾟｯﾄの身分証明書って
おかしいでしょ｡
え？ もってるの？
おかしくない？
What?! It does?!
Isn't that odd?!
なんか普通におかしくない？
Isn't this pretty odd?!
ﾋﾒｶ｡
ﾘｾ｡
ﾊﾂﾞｷ｡
Himeka...
Rise...
Hazuki...
って
どんだけｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗ行ってんだよ！
How many different hostess
clubs have you been to?!
[Note: Girls at hostess clubs usually have their own business cards for their customer to call. More business cards implies more hostess clubs.]
ﾊｯﾊｯ しかたがないな ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
Elizabeth is so hopeless.
しかし そのようなものを
どこで手に入れたのだ？
But where did you get those things?
決まってんだろうが！
ｶﾈとｵｯｻﾝの欲望渦巻く➡
Isn't that obvious?!
They came from society's nighttime outlet where
money and the lust of old men come together!
夜の社交場で手に入れたんだよ！
But this is perfect, Gin-san.
でも いいですよ 銀さん｡
The normal Elizabeth would
never go to those places.
ふだんのｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽだったら
そんなところには行かない｡
あとひと押しで
桂さんも気づくはずです｡
One more push and Katsura-san
will notice!
Now, we'd like you to fill out a
survey concerning your pet.
じゃあ 今度は
ちょっとお宅のﾍﾟｯﾄについての➡
ｱﾝｹｰﾄを書いてほしいんですね｡
ﾌﾑ｡
Why are you filling it out?!
なんでお前が書いてんの？
つ～か ﾛｼｱ語？
And it's in Russian?!
Please look at this, Katsura-san!
見てください 桂さん｡
これがあなたの横にいる➡
This is the truth of the unknown
organism next to you!
得体の知れない生物の真実です｡
気づいてください｡
Please wake up!
あなたのｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽが
ﾛｼｱ語を書きますか？
Can your Elizabeth write in Russian?!
これが あなたの知ってる
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽだと思ってるんですか？
Is this the Elizabeth you know?!
Th-This is...
こ これは…｡
Y-You...
お前｡
I'm so happy, Elizabeth!
嬉しいぞ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！
(銀時/新八)え～っ！
なんでですか？
Why?!
There's obviously something wrong here!
どう考えても
これおかしいでしょ｡
Your Elizabeth can't write in Russian!
あんたのｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽは
ﾛｼｱ語書けないでしょうが！
看板にしか
文字を書かなかったお前が➡
You've finally gone from someone
who could only write on that sign
ついに
紙に書けるようになったのだな｡
to someone who can write on paper!
(銀時/新八)って そこかよ！
That's your concern?!
This is wonderful...
ﾎﾝﾄによかった｡ 毎度まいど
看板がｺﾞﾐになって➡
I was starting to get sick of constantly
throwing away signs.
いいかげん
辟易していたところだったのでな｡
He just revealed how he really felt.
ｻﾗｯと本音言ったよ この人｡
つ～か その回想に出てるのと➡
And why don't you realize that the Elizabeth in that
flashback isn't the one next to you, dumbnuts!
今隣にいるのが
別物だって気づけ ﾎﾞｹ！
よし いこうｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
この国の未来は明るい｡
Let us go, Elizabeth!
This country has a bright future!
ﾊｯﾊｯ｡
どうしましょう｡
What do we do?
全然気づくどころか 一点の疑いも
持ってませんよ 桂さん｡
Forget about waking him up...
Katsura-san doesn't feel the
slightest hint of doubt.
まったく お手上げだよ｡
Man...
I give up.
まだ手はあるかもしんねえな｡
There may still be a way.
Hey there, big guy.
は～い そこのお兄さん｡
[Hostess Club SMILE]
何用だ｡
かわいい子いますよ｡
What do you want?
We've got some cute girls.
今ならお侍さんとﾍﾟｯﾄ割引で半額｡
どうです？
Right now, a samurai accompanied
by a pet gets in for half the price.
How about it?
ﾌﾝ｡ ｵﾚのような侍に そのような
女子との戯れごとは必要ない｡
A samurai like myself would never have
time to fool around with such women.
いくぞｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
ｽﾊｰ ｽﾊｰ｡
Let's go, Elizabeth.
Yes, two coming in!
は～い ２名様 ご案内｡
Elizabeth...?
ｴﾘ… ｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
や～ん いらっしゃい｡
今日はたっぷりｻｰﾋﾞｽするわよ～ん｡
Why welcome!
We'll take extra special
care of you today!
心ゆくまで楽しんでね～ん｡
Enjoy yourselves.
２名様 ご案内で～す｡
Party of two coming in!
(おりょう)ｱｯﾊｯﾊｯ｡
Please, you're such a kidder, sir!
やだ ﾎﾝﾄお客さんおもしろい｡
It's Elizabeth, not sir.
お客さんじゃない｡ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽだ｡
(お妙)どういうこと 新ちゃん？
What's going on, Shin-chan?
桂さんと一緒にいたのって
あんな感じだったっけ？
Was that how the thing with
Katsura-san always was?
まぁ いろいろあって｡
W-Well, it's a long story...
《でもいい作戦です｡ 銀さん｡
But this is a great plan, Gin-san.
あの偽ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽは 確実にｷｬﾊﾞｸﾗ好き｡
The fake Elizabeth is obviously
a fan of hostess clubs.
明らかに
本物とは差がありますからね｡
An obvious difference from the real thing.
桂さんは戸惑っているはずです》
Katsura-san should be confused.
で… では ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ
そろそろ行こうか｡
Th-Then Elizabeth, shall we get going?
あら桂さん もう帰るの？
珍しく遊びにきてくれたのに｡
Oh, Katsura-san?
You're already leaving?
It's so rare of you to come visit.
国の行く末を案じる者
そう長くは戯れていられんのでな｡
As a citizen who's concerned
about the future of this nation,
I have no time to play around.
さぁ 帰るぞ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
Let us go, Elizabeth.
すみませ～ん こちらのお客さん
延長お願いしま～す！
Excuse me!
This customer wants an extension!
延長だと!?
何を言っているのだ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！
An extension?!
What are you saying, Elizabeth?!
Wh-What's wrong, Elizabeth?
ど… どうしたというのだ ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ｡
いつものお前とは
違うじゃないか…｡
You're not your usual self!
そうなんですよ桂さん！
さっきから言ってるけど➡
That's right, Katsura-san!
That's what we've been trying to tell you!
このｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽは
あなたの知ってるｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽじゃない！
This isn't the Elizabeth you know!
そうね！ 似ても似つかぬﾊﾟﾁﾓﾝね！
That's right!
It's a completely different fake!
いい加減 目を覚ませ！
Wake up already!
わかった｡
目を覚ますために顔を洗って…｡
I understand...
I'll go wash my face to wake myself up!
(銀時たち)
そういう意味じゃねえ!!
That's not what we meant!
(桂)いや ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽはｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽであって
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ以外の何ものでもないと｡
No, Elizabeth is Elizabeth
and nothing but Elizabeth.
ものすごい
動揺を見せていましたけど➡
He seemed really disturbed...
Did we bring Katsura-san to his senses?
ちゃんと気づけたんでしょうか？
桂さん｡
さあな… でも➡
Beats me.
But he should have noticed that
thing isn't Elizabeth by now.
これで ようやく
気づいたんじゃねえか？
ｱｲﾂが ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽじゃねえことに｡
(お妙)すみませ～ん！
Excuse me!
This customer wants a bottle
of Dom Perignon Rose!
[Note: Often served at Hostess
Clubs at super high price.]
こちらのお客さんから
ﾋﾟﾝﾄﾞﾝ１本 入りました～｡
And a fruit plate, a whole ham,
and order out for sushi!
あと ﾌﾙｰﾂ盛りに生ﾊﾑに➡
それと お寿司
出前とってくださ～い！
ちょっと！
ｱﾝﾀ いい加減にしなさいよ！
Hey! Cut this out already!
いくら何でも
図に乗りすぎでしょうが！
You're really starting to push it!
お前な ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽじゃないだけでも
詐欺行為だってのに➡
Hey!
You're already running one scam
by pretending to be Elizabeth,
そのうえ
無銭飲食でもするつもりか!?
and now you're going to gorge
yourself without paying!
食欲の追いはぎか この野郎！
This bastard's an appetite robber!
If you're gonna drink that much, you should
be buying us a round, fake Elizabeth!
そんくらい飲ますなら
こっちにも おごってみやがれ！
この 偽ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽが！
[Order whatever you want]
え？
[Why don't YOU play around in grand style?]
[Note: Impersonating Johnny Kitagawa, the founder and former president of Johnny & Associates, a famous male talent agency.]
Uh, but...
いや… でも…｡
Woo-hoo!
(銀時たち)ｲﾔｯﾎｰｲ!!
ﾁｮﾒﾁｮﾒｰ！
ｳﾌﾌ… お客さん ｴｯﾁ！
You're such an animal, champ!
もう ﾎﾝﾄ ｲﾔだわ！
お客さんたらぁ｡
You're incorrigible, champ!
お客さんじゃねえ
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさんだろ～！
It's Elizabeth-san, not champ!
ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽさん
他に何か頼みましょうか？
Elizabeth-san! Would you
like anything else?!
[Let's go to Oke-Kara after this!!]
[Note: "Oke-kara" is Karaoke in TV producer terms]
Woo-hoo! One more round!
(みんな)ｷｬｯﾎｰｲ！ ｱﾌﾀｰ ﾄﾞｰﾝ!!
(銀時たち)ｴﾘｻﾞﾍﾞｽ！
Elizabeth!
(桂)お前…｡
You...
ｴﾘ… ｻﾞﾍﾞｽ…｡
Elizabeth...
♪♪～
["Katsura-san..."]
You dropped your TS.
ＴＳ 落ちてるよ｡
You shouldn't be dropping
something so expensive.
ﾀﾞﾒじゃないか
そんな高価なものを落としては｡
そんなことでは いつか もっと
大切な何かを失ってしまうぞ｡
At this rate, you'll end up losing
something more important.
ＴＳしかり 友達しかりだ｡
Treasure your TS as you
would your friends.
ﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯﾊｯ！
(桂)ｷﾞｬｰｯ!!
《ふあ～… って 臭っ！
Whoa, that stinks!
おい なんか 臭えぞ｡
Hey, something stinks.
うっ… ｲﾃﾃﾃ｡
Ouch...
ん？ なんだ ここ？
Huh? What is this place?
どこだ？ …って 押し入れか？
Where am I?
Wait, the closet?
ん？ なんで こんなとこで
寝てたんだよｵﾚ》
Why was I sleeping in here?
《おっと 足元がﾌﾗつくな｡
ゆうべ そんなに飲んだっけ？
Whoa, I can barely stand straight.
Did I drink that much last night?
しっかし 何だよ このﾆｵｲ…｡
なんで こんなに香ばしいの？
And what's with the smell?
Why is it so strong?
新八のﾔﾂ
ﾎﾟｯﾌﾟｺｰﾝﾊﾟｰﾃｨｰでも勝手にした？
Did Shinpachi hold a popcorn
party without me?
それとも神楽の酢こんぶが
どっかで腐ってんのか？
Or did Kagura's pickled seaweed
spoil somewhere?
あ～ なんか汗臭え｡
頭痛くなってきた｡
Man, it smells like sweat.
My head's starting to hurt.
Hey! Kagura!
お～い 神楽！
あれ？ 神楽… なんだ？
Huh?
Kagu-
What? Something's wrong
with my throat.
ﾉﾄﾞの調子がおかしいな｡ 酒ﾔｹか？
Did I drink too much?
ﾁｯ… しゃあねえな｡ 薬飲も 薬｡
No choice then.
I'll take some medicine.
たしか和室の
引き出しの中にあったよな 薬箱｡
Pretty sure the medicine was
in a drawer in the living room.
I'll just find something random to take...
なんか適当に見繕って…｡
あっ あれ!?
いや 今 ｵﾚいなかった？
H-Huh?
Wasn't that me? Huh?
あれ？ あんなとこにｵﾚ
鏡とか置いたっけ？
Huh? Did I leave a mirror there?
いや ねえよな｡
あれ？ ｵﾚ もしかして➡
No, I didn't...
Huh? Did I leave my body?
幽体離脱でもしちゃってる？
いや でも さっき頭打ったし｡
No, but I just hit my head, so I've got a body.
肉体あるよね｡
って～ もしかして ﾄﾞｯﾍﾟﾙｹﾞﾝｶﾞｰ？
Wait, maybe it's a doppelganger?
いやいやいや
この前までの たまのﾔﾂで➡
No, no, no, no.
We had plenty of that with
the recent Tama incident.
そのへんの感じは
散々やったし ないな～い｡
さすがに ここのｽﾀｯﾌ
ﾈﾀなくても➡
The staff isn't going to reuse that
gag, even if they're out of ideas.
They'd wait a little longer...
そんな かぶりそうなﾈﾀ もう少し
間隔あけてやるだろうし｡
Uh, excuse me...
あの～ すみません ｵﾚ➡
Sorry to disturb myself
while I'm sleeping,
気持よさそうに寝てるところ
申し訳ないですけど➡
ちょっと状況 見えてこないんで
あの～ ｵﾚ➡
but I'm having a hard time understanding
the situation here.
Can I wake myself up?
起きてもらってもいいですか？
ね！ え？ 何これ？
Hello?
Hmm?
Er? What's this?
え？ 何？
この愛らしい… に… 肉球!?
What's with the cute p-paw?
Huh? Huh?
え？ えっ あ… ｳｿ！
N-No way!
え？ ｳｿ！ なんで!?
いやん 毛深い｡
What? No way!
Why?!
Whoa, thick fur!
いや そういう問題じゃなくて｡
え～っ！ ないないない｡
No, that's not the issue here...
What?!
No, no, no, no.
これは な～い｡ ありえないよ｡
意味がわからな～い｡
No way, man.
This is impossible!
I don't get it!
おい 起きろ ｵﾚ！
Hey! Wake up!
I can't be sleeping at a time like this!
ｵﾚが こんな時に
寝てる場合じゃねえんだよ ｵﾚ！
起きろ～！》
Wake up!
え？
んっ｡
ん～っ！
Stop!
《やめて～!!》
["It's What's On The Inside That Counts,
But Only To A Certain Extent"]
《おいおい
どうすんだよ どうすんの？
Hey, hey.
What am I supposed to do now?
これ どう見てもｵﾚだよ｡
ｵﾚが定春で 定春がｵﾚ｡
This is obviously me.
I'm Sadaharu and Sadaharu's me.
[Note: Play on the title of the book "I'm Her And She's Me"]
なんでｵﾚがｵﾚの着替えを
させねえといけねえんだよ｡
Why do I have to change myself?
だいたい こういう場合は…》
((ない～！))
Besides, the usual pattern is...
It's gone!
《ってなるのがﾊﾟﾀｰﾝだろ｡
でもｵﾚ 今ついてるもの｡
Something like that, right?
But it's there.
いつもよりﾋﾞｯｸﾞな現実が
股間にぶら下がってるもの｡
The real deal is hanging
a little bigger than usual.
Usually, you switch with a cute girl
for some hubba hubba To Love-ru.
[Note: Reference to the love comedy
manga "To Love Ru".]
普通は こういう場合
かわいい女の子と入れ替わって➡
ｳｯﾊｳﾊｰのﾄﾞｯｷﾞﾏｷﾞｰの
ﾄｩ ﾗﾌﾞになるもんだろ｡
つうか定春 ﾃﾒｴ お前なんで
こんな時に ｸﾞｰｽｶ寝れんの!?
And Sadaharu! Why are
you still sleeping?!
だんだん腹が立ってきた｡
叩き起こしてやる！
I'm starting to get pissed off.
I'll beat him awake!
Damn, I look fine!
あ～もう いい男じゃないの｡
殴れねえ 殴れねえよ ｵﾚだもの｡
I can't hit that face!
I mean, it's me!
But what am I supposed to do then?!
あ～ でも だからって
どうすりゃいいんだよ～》
朝からﾊﾞﾀﾊﾞﾀうるさいね｡
定春 何やってるｱﾙか？
What's with all the noise this early?
Sadaharu, what are you doing?
Kagura!
《神楽！
ちょうどよかった｡ あっ》
Perfect timing!
どうしたね 銀ちゃん｡
What's wrong, Gin-chan?
Did you finally snap?
頭おかしくなったｱﾙか？
なんか変ね｡
You're acting funny.
That's right, Kagura!
《そう 神楽！
いいとこ気づいた｡ こっち見て！
Way to notice!
Look over here!
銀ちゃん こっち》
二日酔いｱﾙか？
Gin-chan's over here!
Though Gin-chan's also over there,
but Gin-chan's also over here!
You hung over?
つうか なんか臭いね｡
和室のほうｱﾙね｡
And something stinks.
It's coming from the living room.
《ﾀﾞﾒ！ 今 和室はﾀﾞﾒ!!
No!
You can't go to the living room right now!
That Sadaharu, or it was me, I guess...!
さっき ｵﾚだけど
定春の野郎が！》
銀ちゃん…｡
Gin-chan...
This is beyond sad.
いくらなんでも これはひどいｱﾙ｡
自分で片づけてほしいｱﾙ｡
I would hope that you could
clean up after yourself.
あと しばらく
近づかないでくれるｱﾙか｡
And could you stay away from
me for the time being,
bed-shitting samurai?
寝ｸﾞｿ侍｡
《誤解だ～！
You've got it wrong!
知ってるでしょ 神楽ちゃん！
You should know, Kagura-chan!
銀さん ふだんはｸﾞﾀﾞｸﾞﾀﾞでも
しめるときは しめる男だよ！
Gin-san may be a slob, but he knows
how to keep his stuff inside!
肛門だって ちゃんと しめるよ｡
これ ｵﾚだけど➡
He keeps his ass tight and shut, too.
It's me, but it's not my fault!
ｵﾚのせいじゃないよ！》
定春 なに言ってるｱﾙか？
Sadaharu, what are you trying to say?
寝ｸﾞｿがうつるから
早く こっちおいで 定春｡
Hurry over here before you catch
his bed-shitting habits, Sadaharu.
I wasn't talking to you!
お前じゃないね！
Gin-san! I mean, Sadaharu!
《銀さ～ん！ いや 定春！》
Good morning.
おはようございます！
《し… 新八！
Sh-Shinpachi!
お前なら ｵﾚの異変に
気づいてくれるよね？
You should be able to notice
the problem here!
１話から一緒の仲だもの｡
You've been with me since
the first episode!
今まで お前を
ﾀﾞﾒﾀﾞﾒ呼ばわりして悪かったよ｡
I'm sorry about calling
you a lame four-eyes!
お前のﾒｶﾞﾈは
すべてを見通す 真理のﾒｶﾞﾈだ！》
Those glasses are the glasses
of truth which reveal all!
どうしたの？ 定春｡
つ～か ｸｻｯ！ なに このﾆｵｲ｡
What's wrong, Sadaharu?
And something stinks.
What's this smell?
銀さん…｡
Gin-san, I was already
disappointed in you,
もともと見損なってたけど
もっと見損なうことになるとは｡
but I wasn't expecting you to get worse.
あっさりと底値更新です｡
You've reached a new low.
掃除 自分でしろよな｡
《え？ ﾀﾒ口!?》
You better clean this yourself.
What? He's looking down on me?
神楽ちゃん お登勢さんとこで
時間つぶそうよ｡
Kagura-chan, let's go kill time
at Otose-san's place.
そうｱﾙな｡
ここにいたら 寝ｸﾞｿがうつるｱﾙ｡
Let's.
We'll catch his bed-shitting
habits if we stay here.
ｸｿ虫が！
Shitface.
《え～っ!? 定春！
Sadaharu...
なに この銀さんの凋落っぷりは！
入れ替わって わずかな時間で➡
Why is Gin-san's status spiraling down?
How can you humiliate me when we've
only switched places for a little...
お前 どこまで
ｵﾚをおとしめりゃ 気が…｡
入れ替わり!? そうか！
Switched places...
That's it!
入れ替わりといえば
階段落ちだ～！
A switch can be resolved by
falling down a set of stairs!
That's been the typical method
used to end these stories!
入れ替わりﾈﾀは
階段落ちりゃ解決するって➡
昔から決まって…｡
《直ってねぇ～！》
I-It didn't fix anything!
《いいところにいた ﾂﾞﾗ！
ｿｲﾂを止めてくれ！》
Good timing, Zura!
Stop that guy!
｢男子 ３日会わざれば
刮目して見よ｣というが➡
They say that a boy can transform
himself in three days...
Haven't you changed in some way?
おぬし 何か
変わったのではないか？
《そうそう そうだよ！ お前なら
わかってくれると思ってたよ！》
Yes! That's right!
I knew you would understand!
まぁ ここではなんだから➡
Well, we shouldn't stand here and talk
so let's find a place to sit down.
どこか ｢お座り｣
できるところに行くか｡
Though it may take a shake
or two to find a spot,
少し ｢お手｣間はかかるが
こんなところに ずっと➡
but it's better than standing around
like we're trying to play dead.
｢伏せ｣てるわけにもいかんのでな｡
What are you doing, Zura?!
《何やってんだ ﾂﾞﾗ！
How dare you use your conversation
to manipulate me!
なんつ～会話で ｵﾚのこと
操ってくれちゃってんの！
こうなったら
ｼﾞｪｽﾁｬｰでもﾊﾟﾝﾄﾏｲﾑでもして➡
In that case, I'll use gestures or pantomime
to tell him what's going on!
事情を伝えるしか…》
おぉ 定春！
Well, Sadaharu-dono...
《ｷﾓｯ！ ﾂﾞﾗ やめて！
なんで ﾑﾂｺﾞﾛｳさん!?》
Creepy!
Stop, Zura!
Why the Mutsugoro-san impression?!
[Note: Masanori Hata (a.k.a Mutsugoro) is a writer and naturalist. He was an owner of "Mutsugoro Kingdom", a ranch with various animals.]
Such a cutie.
お腹 ﾓﾌﾓﾌさせてもらって
いいですか？
《えっ!?
Can I fluff your stomach?
Stop!
ｲﾔ～ﾝ！ えっ ｲﾔｯ！
I don't wanna admit it!
Don't wanna admit it!
それ 悔しいけど
悔しいけど 感じちゃう！
But it feels so good!
気持いい！ ﾀﾞﾒ ﾀﾞﾒ！ あ～っ!!》
So good!
No! No! Yes!
What a lovely day.
あぁ 今日は いい日だ｡
《あたい 汚されちゃった…｡
I've been violated...
って ちょっ… 定春？
Wait, Sadaharu?
って あの野郎 どこ行ったの!?》
Damn it! Where'd that bastard go?!
(さっちゃん)
なによ その突き刺す視線｡
What's with the penetrating look?
いつもと違うわね｡
いいわ！ しびれるじゃない！
You're not your usual self.
I love it!
You're making me numb!
さぁ いくらでも見下しなさいよ！
踏みつけなさいよ！
Look down on me as much as you want!
Step on me!
今の私は あなたの愛を欲する
哀れなﾒｽ犬！
I'm a poor little bitch who
wants your love!
なに？ その格好｡
What's with that pose?
Don't tell me you want hardcore
play in the middle of town!
まさか！
こんな町中で そんなﾌﾟﾚｰを!?
いいわよ！
すべて受け入れてあげるわ！
Very well!
I'll accept whatever you have to give!
Bring it on!
来なさいよ！
Hurry!
早く！
来…｡
《何やってんだ～!!
Come!
What are you doing?!
時間帯を考えろ 時間帯を！
Do you have any idea what
time this show airs?!
いくら 下ﾈﾀ多いｱﾆﾒだからって
限度があるわ お前ら！
This anime may use a lot of toilet humor,
but there's a line you don't cross!
んなｺｱなﾌﾟﾚｰ
流せるわけねえだろ！》
You can't show this hardcore
freak show on TV!
《ｵﾚも 主人公から いきなり➡
I've changed jobs from the main character
[Note: Changing jobs is a parody of Dragon
Quest, the videogame series.]
１ｸｰﾙに１回
呼んでもらえるかどうかの➡
to a sub-character who might get to
show up once every quarter-year...
ｻﾌﾞｷｬﾗに ｼﾞｮﾌﾞﾁｪﾝｼﾞか…｡
Farewell, fans of Gintoki Sakata...
さようなら 坂田銀時ﾌｧﾝの皆さん｡
こんにちは 定春ﾌｧﾝの皆さん｡
Hello, fans of Sadaharu-kun.
姿かたちは変わっても➡
I may have changed on the outside, but
my soul will continue to shine brightly!
魂は輝き続けます！ 永遠に！》
For eternity!
ﾌｧ～｡
《って 余裕だな おい》
Man, I'm, uh, you're taking this in stride...
Gin-san.
銀さん！ 銀さん 起きてますか？
Gin-san, you awake?
《ん？ あぁ うるせえな 新八｡
Shut up, Shinpachi.
そんなに近くで しゃべんなよ｡
声でけえよ》
Don't talk right next to me.
Your voice is loud.
《あれ？ あれ 定春!?
Huh?
Isn't that Sadaharu?
え？ 定春だったはずのｵﾚの目に
映るはずのない定春を➡
Huh?
I can't be looking at Sadaharu
if I'm Sadaharu,
今 ｵﾚが見てるっていうことは➡
so if I'm looking at Sadaharu,
my eyes can't be Sadaharu's,
ｵﾚの目は 定春の目ではなく…｡
それって もしかして ｵﾚ…｡
which might mean I...
戻ることができた!?
returned to normal...
え？ なにこれ…》
Huh? What's this?
困ったなぁ｡
最近 緩いんだよね このﾒｶﾞﾈ｡
That sucks.
These glasses are getting really loose.
《えぇっ!? …って え！ ﾒｶﾞﾈ!?
Huh!
Er, what?!
Glasses?!
ｵﾚ 今度は ﾒｶﾞﾈになったの!?
I turned into his glasses?!
じゃあ ｵﾚは？
銀さんは いったい何に!?》
Who's Gin-san then?!
銀さん！
いいかげんに起きてくださいよ！
Gin-san, please wake up already!
♪♪～
Noooo!
《ﾉｫ～ｯ!!》
The next episode...
"People Open Up When
They're Locked Up."
[The Odd Jobs gang are trapped in an elevator, with no help in sight...]
[The second half is "Are There Still People Who Go To The Beach And Yell Out 'Bakayaro'"?]
[See you next time.]